AHMED OLAITAN FARUQ

FRONTEND ENGINEER

CAREER OBJECTIVE

Highly skilled and motivated Frontend Developer, experience in creating responsive and visually appealing web applications. Proficient in a wide range of frontend technologies, including HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and modern frameworks/libraries like Vue.js, React and Angular. Strong understanding of user experience (UX) and user interface (UI) design principles, translating them into intuitive and interactive interfaces

EDUCATION

Kwara State Polytechnic. Ilorin, Nigeria.

Higher National Diploma in Computer Science 2019 – 2021.

Kwara State Polytechnic Ilorin, Nigeria.

National Diploma in Computer Science 2015 - 2017.

CORE COMPETENCIES

- Effective communication and team ability
- Proficient in frontend languages and Frameworks(HTML, CSS, Javascript, Typescript,, React, Next.js)
- Excellent problem-solving skills and attention to detail.
- Experience in responsive web design and mobile optimization.
- Self-motivated and proactive with the ability to work independently.
- Familiarity with unit testing tools such as vitest, jest
- Familiar with SEO principles

+2348100319596

Faruqahmedolaitan@gmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/faruq-ahmed-6116 a4232

EXPERIENCE

The OakSoft limited(remote)

Lagos, Nigeria

May 2021- January 2023

- Debugging and optimization of previous websites and up to date.
- Implementing a user-friendly and visually appealing website interface, ensuring seamless navigation.
- Optimize website performance including loading speed and responsiveness.
- Write reusable and efficient code for future

Tublian (remote)

Lagos, Nigeria

Aug 2022 – January 2023

- Had hands on experience working on live project
- Improve existing code base and help open source project solve raised issues
- Improve product documentation for easy readability for developers or users.

Shielded Bit(remote)

London

January 2023 – June 2023

- Had hands on experience working on live project
- Working with other departments to bring business ideas to reality.
- Created the business CRM to help manage clients and content on website

Build Africa(Hybrid)

Lagos, Nigeria

January 2023 – current

- Bringing business E-commerce idea into existence
- Working with woo-commerce headless app by implementing woo-commerce rest API
- Manage app with Nx CI to maintain and scale monorepo applications.

PROJECTS

Build Africa Store: Angular, NgRx

buildafrica.store

- NxgRx Facilitated seamless front-end and back-end communication, also enhanced client side store for reusable data.
- Angular: build the front end on angular, styled with tailwind to ensure seamless and responsive user interface.

Build Core: Tech Stack: Angular, Angular Signals,

BuildCore

BuildCore is a modular web application that ecompeases all operation of the organization, it a CRM and internal operation flow of procurement of building material in Nigeria today.

Key Features and Tools:

- Angular: The frontend is built using Angular, offering a robust framework for building dynamic and responsive UIs.
- Angular Signals: Utilized for reactive state management with fine-grained reactivity and minimal boilerplate.
- Tailwind CSS: Enables rapid UI development with utility-first styling for responsive and modern design.

Strawline: Tech Stack: React, Context API, TanStack Query, Tailwind CSS,

Strawline

Strawline is a modern web application built to deliver a responsive and scalable user experience. It leverages a robust frontend architecture powered by React and a Node.js backend.

Key Features and Tools:

- React: Used for building a fast and modular component-based user interface.
- Context API: Manages local application state, enabling global state sharing across components.
- TanStack Query: Handles efficient data fetching, caching, and synchronization between the client and server.

LEADERSHIP, VOLUNTEERING & EXTRACURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

National Association of Faculty of Management Student

Lagos, Nigeria.

Student Representative Member

 Oversaw all operations of a student led body committed to the advancement and development of over 300 student members.

Design and implementation of a digital library system

Kwara state polytechnic

Team leader

- The project was developed to implement the use of a digital library in Kwara state polytechnic computer science department.
- Lead a group of 25 to a successful implementation of the project.
- Involved with the settings of the library including the system configuration and network connection.